자유로운 집요정 도비
여기 잠들다
It's beautiful here.
참 예쁘다
It was our aunt's.
We used to come here as kids.
숙모 집이었는데
어렸을 때 자주 왔었어
The Order uses it
now as a safe house.
지금은 기사단의
피신처로 쓰고 있지
What's left of us at least.
몇 안 남았지만…
Muggles think these
things keep evil away.
머글들은 이게 귀신을
쫓아 준다고 생각한대
But they're wrong.
I need to talk to the Goblin.
도깨비랑 얘기해 봐야겠어
How are you?
좀 어때요?
Alive.
살아는 있지
기억 못 하겠지만…
You probably don't
remember that you...
That I showed you to your vault,
the first time you came to Gringotts.
그린고트에 처음 왔을 때
내가 금고 보여 준 거?
Even amongst Goblins, you are famous
Harry Potter.
도깨비들한테도 넌 유명해
- You buried the elf?
- Yes.
집요정도 묻어 주고
네
나도 구해 줬고
And brought me here.
You are...
넌 아주
이상한 마법사야
Pretty unusual, is it?
저 칼은
어떻게 손에 넣었지?
How did you come by the sword?
It's complicated.
말하자면 복잡해요
Why did Bellatrix Lestrange think
it should be in her vault at Gringotts?
벨라트릭스는 왜 이게
자기 금고에 있다 생각했죠?
It's complicated.
말하자면 복잡해
칼이 필요할 때
저절로 나타났어요
The sword presented itself to us,
in moment of need.
We didn't steal it.
우리가 훔친 게 아니에요
벨라트릭스 금고에
똑같은 칼이 있는데
There is a sword in Madam Lestrange's
vault identical to this one.
But it is a fake.
그건 가짜야
지난 여름에 누가 바꿔 놨지
It was placed there this past summer.
And she never suspected
it was a fake.
- 가짜인 걸 그녀가 몰랐어요?
- 감쪽같이 똑같거든
The replica is very convincing.
Only a goblin would recognize that
this is the true Sword of Gryffindor.
이게 진짜라는 건
도깨비만이 알 수 있지
누가 바꿔 놨죠?
Who is the acquaintance?
호그와트의 교수
내가 알기론 이제 교장이지
A Hogwarts Professor.
As I understand that
he's now Headmaster.
스네이프?
Snape.
He put a fake sword
in Bellatrix's vault.
그가 가짜 칼을
넣어 놨다고요?
왜요?
Why?
그린고트 금고들에는
이상한 물건들이 많아
There are more than a few curious things
in the vaults at Gringotts.
벨라트릭스의 금고에도?
And in Madam Lestrange's
vault as well?
Perhaps.
어쩌면
금고 안에
들어가 봐야겠어요
I need to get into Gringotts.
Into one of the vaults.
불가능해
- It is impossible.
- Alone, yes.
나 혼자면 그렇겠지만
당신하고 가면 아니죠
But with you, no.
왜 내가 도와줘야 하지?
- Why should I help you?
- I have gold.
나한테는 금이 아주 많아요
Lots of it.
- 금에는 관심 없어
- 그럼요?
I've no interest in gold.
Then what?
저거
That.
저걸 줘
That is my price.
Are you thinking there's a
Horcrux in Bellatrix's vault?
벨라트릭스 금고에
호크룩스가 있다고 생각해?
우리가 금고에
들어간 줄 알고 놀라서
Well, she was terrified when she
thought we had been in there.
뭘 가져갔냐고
계속 캐물었잖아
She kept asking you,
what else was taken?
'그'의 영혼 조각인
호크룩스가 있는 거야
I bet you anything, there's Horcrux
in there. Another piece of his soul.
그걸 찾아서 파괴해야 해
Let's find it, kill it, and we are
one step closer to killing him.
어떻게?
And what happens when we find it,
도깨비한테
칼을 줘 버렸잖아
How're we supposed to destroy it,
now you're giving the sword to Griphook?
방법을 생각해 볼게
I'm still working on that part.
약한 상태셔
He's weak.
뭐냐?
Who?
올리밴더 아저씨
물어볼 게 있어요
Mr. Ollivander
I need to ask you a few questions.
뭐든지 물어보렴
Anything, m'boy.
Anything!
이게 어떤 지팡이죠?
사용해도 안전한가요?
Would you mind identifying this wand?
We need to know if it's safe to use.
Uhh... Walnut
호두나무
용의 심장
Dragon Heartstring
32센티미터
12 and three quarter inches.
견고하고
Unyie...
아주 단단해
Unyielding.
벨라트릭스의 지팡이
This belonged to Bellatrix Lestrange.
조심해서 다루렴
이건요?
And this?
산사나무
Hawthorn.
유니콘의 털
An unicorn hair.
25센티미터, 적당한 탄력성
10 inches.
Reasonably pliant.
드레이코 말포이의
지팡이였어
This was the wand of Draco Malfoy.
그래요? 이제는 아니고요?
Was?
Is it not still?
아니지, 네가 빼앗았으니까
Well, perhaps not.
If you won it from him.
지팡이가 새 주인을 맞았군
I sense its allegiance has changed.
지팡이가 감정이 있는 것처럼
말씀하시네요
You talk about wands,
as if they have feelings...
생각도 하고…
... can think!
지팡이는 마법사를 선택해
The wand chooses the wizard, Mr.
Potter.
지팡이학을 연구한 이들이
모두 인정한 사실이지
That much has always been clear to
those of us who've studied wandlore.
죽음의 성물에 대해
뭘 아시죠?
And, what do you know
about the Deathly Hallows?
소문에 의하면 3가지야
It is rumored there are three.
딱총나무 지팡이
The Elder Wand, the Cloak of Invisibility,
to hide you from your enemies...
적에게서 몸을 숨길
투명 망토
죽은 사람을 살리는
부활의 돌
and the Resurrection Stone, to bring
back loved ones from the dead.
그 셋을 모두 가지면
죽음의 지배자가 되지
Together,
they make one the Master of Death.
하지만 진짜 있다고
믿는 사람은 드물어
But few,
truly believe that such objects exist.
아저씨는요?
Do you?
진짜 있다고 믿으세요?
Do you believe they exist, sir?
Well...
옛사람들이 꾸며낸 얘기를
믿을 이유가 없지
I see no reason to put
stock into an old wives' tale.
거짓말 마세요
You're lying!
하나의 존재는 아시잖아요
You know one exists.
'그'에게 말해 줬고요
You told him about it.
You told him about the Elder Wand...
딱총나무 지팡이를
어디서 찾을 수 있는지…
and where he could go looking for it.
He tortured me.
나를 고문했다
게다가
Besides...
난 소문을 전했을 뿐이야
... I only conveyed rumors.
'그'가
There's...
그 지팡이를 찾는다는
보장도 없고
There's no telling
whether he will find it.
벌써 찾았어요
He has found it, sir.
그만 쉬세요
We'll let you rest.
'그'가 너를 노린다, 포터 군
He's after you, Mr. Potter.
네 말처럼 '그'가
딱총나무 지팡이를 찾았다면
If it's true what you say,
that he has the Elder Wand,
I'm afraid,
유감스럽게도
넌 '그'의 적수가 안 돼
... you really don't stand a chance.
그럼 당하기 전에
먼저 죽여야겠군요
Well, I suppose I'll have to kill him,
before he finds me, then.
벨라트릭스 머리카락 맞아?
You're sure that's hers?
Positive.
확실해
어때?
Well?
비슷해 보여?
How do I look?
끔찍하다
Hideous.
헤르미온느한테 칼을 줘요
You can give that to Hermione to hold.
Alright, Griphook?
당신을 믿을게요, 그립훅
We're relying on you, Griphook.
그곳에 데려다준다면
칼은 당신 거예요
If you get us past the
guards into the vault...
The sword's yours.
레스트랭 부인
Madam Lestrange.
굿모닝
Good morning.
굿모닝? 굿모닝이라고?
Good morning?
You're Bellatrix Lestrange,
not some school girl!
넌 벨라트릭스지
순진한 여학생이 아니야
Hey!
Easy!
진정해요
들켜서 잡히느니
그 칼로 자살하는 게 나아
If she gives us away, we must swear to
use that sword to slit our own throats.
알아들어?
Understand?
도깨비 말이 맞아
내가 바보 같았어
No, he's right.
I speak stupid.
좋아
Okay.
Let's do it.
해보자
내 금고에 들어가겠다
I wish to enter my vault.
신분증 좀?
Identification?
그런 거 확인할 필요 없어
I hardly think that
would be necessary.
레스트랭 부인
Madam Lestrange.
I don't like to be kept waiting.
난 기다리는 건 질색이야
눈치챘어
I know...
가짜인 걸 알아
They know she's an impostor.
침입자 경고를 받은 거야
They'd be warned.
해리?
Harry...
어떡하지?
What do we do, Harry?
레스트랭 부인
지팡이 좀 주십시오
Madam Lestrange,
would you mind presenting your wand?
왜 그래야 하지?
And why should I do that?
규정입니다, 이해하십시오
상황이 상황인지라
It's the bank's policy! I'm sure you
understand, given current climate.
아니
No! I most certainly
do not understand!
이해 못 하겠어
죄송하지만
I'm afraid, I must insist.
지팡이를 주십시오
임페리오
Imperio!
좋습니다, 절 따라오십시오
Very well, Madam Lestrange.
If you will follow me?
저게 뭐죠?
What is that, Griphook?
그립훅
Griphook!
Aresto Momentum
어레스토 모멘툼!
잘했어
Well done, Hermione.
원래 모습으로 돌아왔어
Oh no, you two're like you again.
도둑 방지용 폭포인데
모든 마법을 해제시켜
The Thief's Downfall,
washes away all enchantments.
치명적이지
Can be deadly.
말해 뭐 하겠어요
You don't say.
여길 나가는
다른 방법이 있나요?
Just out of interest,
is there any other way out of here?
없어
No.
여기서 뭐 하는 거야?
What the devil are all
you doing down here?
도둑이구나!
Thieves!
- 넌 여길 그만두고…
- 임페리오!
You gave up the.....
-Imperio
-You!
느낌이 불길해
That doesn't sound good.
제길
Bloody hell!
우크라이나 아이론벨리야
That's an Ukrainian Ironbelly.
여기
Here.
소음을 들으면
고통받게 훈련돼 있어
It's been trained to expect pain
when it hears the noise.
너무 야만적이에요
That's barbaric!
루모스
Lumos
젠장
Blimey!
아씨오 호크룩스
Accio Horcrux
전에도 실패해 놓고
또 하냐?
You seem you're gonna try
that one to get over here?
그런 마법은 여기서 안 통해
No kind of magic would work in here.
호크룩스가
여기 있어, 해리?
It's in here, Harry?
느껴져?
Can you feel anything?
저 잔이야! 저 위에!
That's it!
Up there!
복제 저주를 걸어 놨어
손대면 배로 늘어나
They have added the Gemino curse.
Everything you touch will multiply.
칼을 줘!
Give me the sword.
움직이지 마!
Stop moving!
집어!
Do it!
약속했잖아요!
- We had deal, Griphook!
- The cup for the sword!
먼저 칼을 내놔
들어오게 해준다고 했지
나가게 해준다는 약속은 안 했어
I said I'll get you in, I didn't
say anything about getting you out.
그립훅!
Griphook! Thieves!
Griphook!
- 도둑이야!
- 그립훅!
Hey, thieves!
도둑이야!
다른 도깨비를
이용해 빠져나가자
Is that okay?
We've still got Bogrod.
안됐네
That's unfortunate.
서둘러야 해
좋은 방법 없어?
We can't just stand here,
You got any idea?
똑똑한 건 너잖아!
You're the brilliant one.
방법이 있긴 한데
미친 짓이야
I've got something, but it's mad!
리덕토
Reducto
빨리!
Well, come on, then!
레라시오
Relashio
움직인다!
Keep moving!
이제 어떡해?
Now what?
리덕토
Reducto
꽉 잡아!
Hold on.
That was brilliant!
Absolutely brilliant!
끝내준다, 완전 끝내줬어!
내려간다!
We're dropping!
- 뛰어내려!
- 언제?
- I say we jump!
- When?
Now!
지금!
'그'가 알고 있어
He knows.
You-Know-Who.
우리가 금고에
몰래 들어갔고
He knows we broke into Gringotts.
He knows what we took,
and he knows we're hunting Horcruxes.
호크룩스를 찾고 있다는 걸
- 어떻게 알았어?
- 내가 봤어
- How is it you know?
- I saw him.
정신을 연결했었어?
그럼 안돼!
You let him in?
Harry, you can't do that!
Hermione, I can't always help it!
내 의지대로 조절이 안 돼
나도 모르겠다고
Well, maybe I can.
I don't know!
그만 싸워, 그래서?
Never mind!
What happened?
Well, he's angry...
'그'가 화났어
겁도 났고
and scared too.
He knows, if we find and destroy all the
Horcruxes, we'll be able to kill him.
호크룩스를 다 파괴하면
자기를 죽일 수 있으니까
I reckon he'll stop at nothing
to make sure we don't find the rest.
나머지를 못 찾게
모든 수단을 쓸 거야
And there's more.
호크룩스 하나가
호그와트에 있어
One of them is at Hogwarts.
What?
뭐라고?
You saw it?
- 뭘 봤는데?
- 호그와트 성이랑 로웨나 래번클로
I saw the castle.
And Rowena Ravenclaw.
It must have something
to do with her.
그녀와 관계있나 봐
당장 가자
We have to go there, now!
Well, we can't do that!
무작정 갈 수는 없어
계획을 세워야지
We've got to plan,
we've got to figure it out!
Hermione, when have any of
our plans ever actually worked?
우리 계획이
성공한 적 있었어?
We plan, we get there,
all hell breaks loose.
계획만 세우고
매번 허탕쳤잖아
He's right!
One problem...
그건 그래
스네이프가 교장이라
정문으로는 못 갈 거야
Snape's Headmaster now,
we can't just move from the front door!
Well, we'll go to Hogsmeade,
일단 호그스미드
과자 가게로 가서
to Honeydukes.
Take the secret
passage in the cellar.
지하 비밀 통로를 이용하자
It's...
'그'가 이상해졌어
There's something wrong with him.
It's like, you know, in the past...
전에는 그의 생각을
읽을 수 있었는데
I've always been able
to follow his thoughts.
And now everything just
feels disconnected.
지금은 완전히
분리된 기분이야
Maybe it's the Horcruxes.
Maybe he's growing weaker.
호크룩스가 파괴돼서
죽어 가는지도 몰라
Maybe he's dying!
No!
아니, 그것보다는
어디가 아픈 거 같아
No, it's...
it's more like he's wounded.
If anything, he feels more dangerous.
뭐든 간에
위험해진 느낌이야
그 애가 우리 비밀을
알아차려서
우리가 위험해졌다
무슨 수를 써서라도
녀석을 찾아야 해
그리고 넌
내 곁에서 떠나지 마
기피 대상자 1번
해리 포터
- 이곳에 있다!
- 샅샅이 뒤져!
- Right here. Come on!
- Search everywhere.
Go, move!
마구간도!
너희 둘은 따라와
안 보이나?
Faster!
In here, Potter.
여기다, 포터
Come on, move!
Did you look at him?
얼굴 봤어?
- For a second I thought that was...
- I know. Dumbledore!
- 언뜻 봤는데 모습이…
- 덤블도어를 닮았어
Harry?
해리?
I can see you in this.
거울에 네가 보여
Bloody fools,
what were you thinking, coming here?
멍청한 녀석들!
무슨 생각으로 여길 왔어?
Have you any idea
how dangerous it is?
얼마나 위험한지
알기나 해?
You're Aberforth,
Dumbledore's brother.
덤블도어 교수님 동생
애버포스군요
It's you who I've
been seeing in here.
당신이 늘 거울에 보였어요
You're the one who sent Dobby.
도비를 보낸 것도
당신이었고요
- Why've you left him?
- He's dead.
도비는?
죽었어요
Sorry to hear it.
I liked that elf.
안됐군, 착한 녀석이었는데
Who gave that to you?
누가 줬죠? 그 거울?
The mirror?
Mundungus Fletcher, 'bout a year ago.
먼던구스한테서
1년 전에 샀지
Dung had no right selling that to you.
It belongs to...
- 그 거울 주인은…
- 시리우스지
Sirius...
Albus told me.
형한테 들었다
He also told me you'd
likely be hacked off,
내가 가진 걸 알면
네가 화낼 거라 했지만
... if you ever found that I had it.
But, ask yourself;
나한테 이게 없었음
네가 어떻게 됐겠어?
Where would you be if I didn't?
Do you have any others much?
불사조 기사단 소식
들으셨어요?
From the Order?
The Order's finished.
기사단은 끝났어
You-Know-Who's won,
'그'가 이긴 거지
... anyone who says otherwise
is killing themselves.
인정하긴 싫지만
그게 현실이야
We need to get into Hogwarts,
tonight.
오늘 밤, 호그와트에
들어가야 해요
Dumbledore gave us a job to do.
덤블도어가 임무를 줬어요
Did he now...
그래?
Nice job?
Easy?
쉬운 임무야? 간단해?
We've been hunting Horcruxes.
마지막 호크룩스가
And we think the last one's inside
the castle.
그 안에 있어요
들어가게 도와줘요
But we'll need your help getting in.
Which job my brother has given you no,
it's a suicide mission.
임무를 준 게 아니라
자살하라고 시킨 거네
Do yourself a favor, boy.
Go home!
오래 살고 싶으면
집으로 돌아가
Live a little longer.
Dumbledore trusted
me to see this through.
- 덤블도어는 저를 믿으셨어요
- 지금까지 형이 한 말들을
What makes you think
you can trust him?
What makes you think you can believe
anything my brother told you?
다 믿을 수 있어?
And in all the time you knew him...
형이 지금까지
내 얘기를 한 적 있어?
Did he ever mention my name?
Did he ever mentioned hers?
여동생 얘기는?
- Why should he...
- Keep secrets.
- 교수님이 왜…
- 숨겼겠냐고? 나야 모르지
You tell me?
- I trusted him.
- That's a boy's answer.
- 저는 다 믿었어요
- 순진한 녀석
A boy goes chasing Horcruxes on the word of a
man who wouldn't even tell him where to start.
늙은이 말만 믿고 무작정
호크룩스 사냥을 나섰다?
거짓말 마
You're lying!
Not just on me, that doesn't matter.
To yourself as well.
넌 나뿐만 아니라
너 자신도 속이고 있어
That's what a fool does.
바보나 하는 짓이지
You don't strike me as a fool,
Harry Potter!
넌 바보가 아니야
해리 포터
So, I'll ask you again,
there must be a reason.
솔직히 말해 봐
진짜 이유가 뭐지?
I'm not interested in what happened
between you and your brother.
당신과 교수님 일에는
관심 없어요
I don't care that you've given up.
당신이 포기했대도
상관없고요
I trusted the man I knew.
저는 교수님을 믿었고
We need to get into
the castle tonight.
오늘 밤
성에 들어가야 해요
You know what to do.
네 할 일 알지?
Where've you sent her?
어디로 보냈죠?
You'll see.
곧 알게 돼
Soon enough.
That's your sister, Ariana.
Isn't it?
여동생 아리애나죠?
She died very young, didn't she?
어린 나이에 죽었고요?
My brother sacrificed many things,
Mr. Potter.
형은 힘을 얻기 위해
On his journey to find power.
많은 걸 희생시켰다
Including Ariana.
아리애나도…
And she was devoted to him.
걔는 형한테 헌신했고
He gave her everything,
형도 걔한테 모든 걸 줬지
... but time.
시간만 빼고…
Thank you, Mr. Dumbledore.
고맙습니다
He did save our lives twice!
우리를 두 번이나
구해 줬잖아
Kept an eye on us on that mirror.
거울을 통해
우리를 지켜봤고
That doesn't seem like
someone who's given up!
포기했다면 안 그랬겠지
She's coming back.
초상화가 돌아와
What's that with her?
옆에 누구지?
Neville!
네빌!
- How you look...
- Like hell, I reckon.
- 꼴이…
- 알아, 엉망이지?
This is nothing.
시무스에 비하면
이건 약과야
Seamus is worse.
Hey, Ab!
애버포스, 두 명이 더 와요
We've got a couple
more coming through.
Don't remember this
on the Marauder's Map.
비밀 지도에는 없는
통로인데
That's because it
never existed till now.
지금까지는 없었지
The seven secret passages were sealed
off, before the start of the year.
7개의 비밀 통로는
모두 봉쇄됐고
This is the only way in or out, now.
여기가 유일해
The grounds are crawled with
Death Eaters and Dementors.
학교는 죽음을 먹는 자들과
디멘터들이 득실대고
How about Mr. Snape as Headmaster?
스네이프는 어때?
Hardly ever seen.
한 번도 못 봤어
문제는 캐로우 남매야
It's the Carrows who's watch out for.
Carrows?
캐로우?
Yeah. Brother and sister.
Incharge of discipline.
친남매고 규율 담당인데
They like punishment, the Carrows.
벌주는 걸 무지 좋아해
They did that to you?
그들이 이랬어? 왜?
Why?
Today's Dark Arts lesson was
practicing the Cruciatus curse.
우리더러 1학년들에게
저주 마법을 쓰라기에
On first years.
안 하겠다고
I refused.
거부했거든
Hogwarts has changed.
예전의 호그와트가 아니야
Let's have a bit of fun, shall we?
좀 놀라게 해줄까?
Hey, listen up you lot!
얘들아! 깜짝쇼를 준비했어
I've for you a surprise.
No more Aberforth's cook gonna help.
애버포스 요리면 됐어
먹지도 못하잖아
We'll be surprised if
we can digest that.
- Oh my!
- Harry!
맙소사!
Get the word out to Remus and
the others, that Harry is back.
해리가 돌아왔다고
모두에게 알려
Okay, okay!
그만, '그'보다
너희가 먼저 죽이겠다
Let's not kill him
before You-Know-Who does.
... Do you read? We've a new weather report.
Lightning has struck. I repeat: Lightning has struck.
리버, 들리나?
날씨가 변했다, 번개가 쳤다
What's the fun, Harry?
계획이 뭐야?
Okay.
좋아
There's something we need to find.
찾을 물건이 있어
Something hidden here, in the castle.
성에 숨겨져 있는데
'그'를 물리치는 데 도움이 될 거야
And it may help us to defeat
You-Know-Who.
- Alright, what is it?
- We don't know.
알았어, 그게 뭔데?
몰라
- Where is it?
- We don't know that either.
- 어디 있는데?
- 그것도 몰라
I realize there's not much to go on.
- 단서가 별로 없어
- 전혀 없네
That's nothing to go on.
I think it has something
to do with Ravenclaw.
래번클로와 관계있는 거야
It'll be small, easily concealed.
작고, 숨기기 쉽고…
Anyone, any ideas?
짚이는 거 있어?
Well, there's Rowena
Ravenclaw's lost diadem.
래번클로의 보관 아닐까?
Oh, bloody hell!
Here we go!
- 또 시작이네
- 래번클로의 보관?
Lost diadem of Ravenclaw?
Hasn't anyone heard of this?
못 들어 봤어?
아주 유명한데
It's quite famous.
Yes. But, Luna, it's lost.
그건 수백 년 전에
사라졌잖아, 루나
For centuries. There's no person
alive today who's seen it.
산 사람 중에는
그걸 본 사람 없어
Excuse me, can someone tell
me what bloody diadem is?
도대체 보관이 뭔데?
It's a sort of crown.
머리띠처럼 생긴
작은 왕관이야
You know, like a tiara.
Harry!
해리
Hi, there.
안녕
Six months she doesn't see me and
it's like I'm a frankie first-year.
6개월 만에 만났는데
난 유령 취급이네
I'm her brother!
- 이래도 되는 거야?
- 오빠는 여럿이지만
- She's got lots of them, but she's got only one Harry.
- Shut up, Seamus!
- 해리는 하나잖아
- 시끄러워
What is it, Ginny?
왜 그래, 지니?
Snape knows... he knows
that Harry was spotted in Hogsmeade.
해리가 나타난 걸
스네이프가 알아
Many of you are surely wondering,
why I have summoned you at this hour.
이 시간에 소집한 이유가
궁금할 겁니다
It's come to my attention,
that earlier this evening...
보고에 따르면 오늘 저녁
Harry Potter was
sighted in Hogsmeade.
해리 포터가
호그스미드에 나타났어요
Now...
경고하는데
should anyone...
학생이든 교수든
student or staff attempt to aid Mr.
Potter?
포터 군을 도와주려고 하면
They will be punished in a manner consistent with
the severity of their transcription, further more...
사안의 중대성을 감안
큰 벌을 받을 것입니다
또한
Any person found to have
knowledge of these events...
그가 나타난 걸
알고 있으면서
who fails to come forward...
말하지 않은 사람도
... will be treated as equally guilty.
돕는 것에 상응하는
벌을 받을 것입니다
Another...
이제
If anyone in here has any knowledge of
Mr. Potter's movements this evening.
여러분 중에
포터 군의 행방을
아는 사람이 있다면
I invite them to step forward.
앞으로 나와서 솔직하게
Now!
털어놔요
It seems, despite your
exhaustive defensive strategies,
방어 전략을
철저히 세웠을 텐데
... you still have a bit of
security problem, Headmaster.
허점이 참 많네요
교장 선생님
I'm afraid it's quite extensive.
몰래 들어오기
이렇게 쉬우니
How dare you stand where he stood?
감히 덤블도어의
자리를 뺏다뇨
Tell them how it happened that night?
Tell them how you looked him in the eye...
그날 밤 일을
다 말해요!
당신을 믿은 분을
어떻게 죽였는지를!
A man who trusted you,
and killed him.
Tell them!
다 말해요!
COWARD!!!
겁쟁이!
Harry.
해리
Potter?
포터?
I know that many of
you will want to fight.
나와 싸우기를 원하고
Some of you may even think
that to fight is wise.
승산이 있다고
생각하는 자도 있지만
But this is folly.
어리석은 짓이다
Give me Harry Potter.
해리 포터를 넘겨라
Do this and none shall be harmed.
그럼 나머지는
무사할 것이다
Give me Harry Potter,
and I shall leave Hogwarts untouched.
해리 포터를 내놓으면
호그와트는 안 건드리겠다
Give me Harry Potter,
and you will be rewarded.
해리 포터를 넘기면
상을 내리겠다
You have one hour.
1시간 주겠다
What're you waiting for?
Someone grab him!
뭘 꾸물대?
해리를 잡아!
Students out of bed!
학생들이 일어났습니다!
학생들이 잠자리를 벗어나
Students in the corridor!
복도에 나왔습니다!
They're supposed to be out of bed,
you blithering idiot!
이유가 있으니 나왔죠
이 얼간이!
Sorry ma'am.
죄송합니다
As it happens, Mr. Filch...
때마침 잘 왔어요, 필치 씨
Your arrival is most opportune.
If you would, I would like you please, to lead Miss
Parkinson and the rest of Slytherin house, from the hall.
파킨슨 양과
슬리데린 학생들을
복도에서 데려가요
Exactly where is it I'll
be leading 'em to, ma'am?
어디로요?
The dungeons would do.
지하 감옥이 좋겠군요
네
전부 따라와!
I presume you have a reason
for returning, Potter.
돌아온 이유가 있겠지
뭐가 필요하니?
What is it you need?
Time, Professor.
As much as you can get me.
시간요, 최대한 많이요
Do what you have to do.
어서 가렴
난 성을 방어하마
I'll secure the castle.
Potter...
포터
It's good to see you.
반갑구나
It's good to see you too, Professor.
저도요, 교수님
Hold the fort, Neville.
물러서지 마, 네빌
Harry!
Hermione and I've been thinking,
it doesn't matter if we find a Horcrux.
헤르미온느랑 생각해 봤는데
호크룩스를 찾아도
아무 소용없어
What do you mean?
- 무슨 소리야?
- 파괴할 수 없잖아
Unless we can destroy it.
So, we were thinking...
그래서 말인데…
Well, Ron was thinking,
it was Ron's idea.
론이 생각한 건데
아주 끝내줘
It's completely brilliant.
You destroyed Tom Riddle's diary
with a Basilisk's fang, right?
뱀 송곳니로
톰 리들 일기장을 파괴했잖아?
Well, me and Hermione did remind
where we might find one.
우리가 찾아올게
그걸로 파괴할 수 있어
Okay.
좋아
Okay, but take this.
이걸 가져가
돌아와서 날 찾을 수 있게
That way,
you can find me when you get back.
Where're you going?
어디 가?
Ravenclaw common room,
Gotta start somewhere.
래번클로 휴게실부터
찾아볼게
Harry!
해리! 해리!
Let me get this straight,
Professor...
진짜요, 교수님?
정말 하라고요?
You're actually giving us
permission to do this?
That is correct, Longbottom.
그래, 롱바텀
To blow it up!
Boom!
다리를 폭파시켜요?
그래!
Wicked!
재미있겠네요
근데 어떻게요?
But how on earth are
we gonna do that?
Why don't you confer with Mr.
Finnigan?
시무스와 상의해 봐
As I recall, he has a particular
proclivity for pyro-technics.
폭죽놀이에 미친
녀석이니까
I can bring it down.
문제없어요
That's the spirit!
Away, you go.
그래야지, 어서 가 봐
You do realize, of course, we can't
keep out You-Know-Who indefinitely.
교수님도 아시겠죠?
'그'를 영원히 막을 수는 없어요
That doesn't mean we can't delay him.
지체시킬 수는 있죠
And his name is Voldemort.
Filius, you might as well use it.
볼드모트라고
이름을 불러도 괜찮아요
He's come to try to kill you,
either way!
이러나저러나
죽이려 할 테니까
Piertotum Locomotor.
피에르토툼 로코모토르
Hogwarts is threatened.
호그와트가 위험하다
Man the boundaries! Protect us.
Do your duty...
학교를 방어하고 우리를 보호해라!
너희 의무를 다해라!
... to our school.
I've always wanted to use that spell!
항상 써 보고 싶던
주문이에요
Protego Maxima
프로테고 막시마, 피안토 듀리
레펠로 이니미컴
Fianto Duri
Repello Inimigotum
Protego Maxima
Fianto Duri
Repello....
Protego Maxima
Fianto Duri
Repello Inimigotum
Protego Maxima
프로테고 막시마
Harry, wait!
- 해리, 기다려! 할 얘기가 있어
- 시간 없어, 루나
I need to talk to you!
- I'm a bit pre-occupied at the moment, Luna.
- You don't know anything where you're going.
지금 가는 곳에는
아무것도 없어
You're wasting your time!
Look, we'll talk later, okay, Luna?
- 나중에 얘기해
- 해리!
- Harry?
- Later.
Harry Potter,
you listen to me right now!
- 나중에!
- 해리 포터!
내 말 들어!
Do you remember what Cho said
about Rowena Ravenclaw's diadem?
초가 보관에 대해
했던 말 기억해?
There is not a person
alive who's seen it.
"산 사람 중에는
그걸 본 사람 없어"
It's obvious, isn't it?
그러니까
죽은 사람한테 물어봐야지
We have to talk to
someone who's dead.
It's very impressive, isn't it?
대단하지 않아?
If you've to find her,
you'll find her down there.
저 밑에 있을 거야
- Aren't you coming?
- No.
- 넌?
- 단둘이
I think it's best if
you two talk alone.
얘기하는 게 좋을 거 같아
She's very shy.
수줍음이 많거든
You're the Grey Lady.
회색 숙녀군요
The ghost of Ravenclaw tower.
래번클로 탑의 유령
I do not answer to that name!
그 별명에는 대답 안 해
No, I'm sorry, I'm sorry!
죄송해요, 이름이 헬레나죠?
헬레나 래번클로
It's Helena, isn't it?
Helena Ravenclaw, Rowena's daughter.
로웨나의 따님
Are you a friend of Luna's?
루나 친구니?
Yes.
네
And she thought you
might be able to help me.
당신이 도와줄 거랬어요
You seek my mother's diadem?
우리 어머니의
보관을 찾는구나
Yes.
네
That's right.
맞아요
Luna is kind.
루나는 친절해
다른 학생들하곤 달라
Unlike so many of the others.
But she was wrong, I cannot help you!
그렇지만 틀렸어
난 못 도와줘
Wait, please!
잠깐만요!
I want to destroy it!
그걸 파괴할 거예요!
They never learn.
나와 싸우겠다?
Such a pity.
유감이군
But, my Lord...
하지만, 주인님
Shouldn't we wait?
기다리는 게
좋지 않을까요?
My Lord!
주인님
Begin!
공격해라
I thought you want to do it.
Isn't it, Helena?
당신도 그걸 원하죠?
You want to destroy it?
보관이 파괴되길…
Another swore to destroy it,
many years ago.
오래전에도
이상한 이름을 가진 꼬마가
A strange boy with a strange name.
그걸 파괴하겠다고 했어
Tom Riddle.
- 톰 리들
- 나를 속였지
But he lied.
He's lied to many people.
많은 사람을 속였어요
I know what he's done!
I know who he is!
그가 한 짓을 알아
그가 누군지도!
He defiled it, with dark magic!
어둠의 마법으로
보관을 더럽혔어
I can destroy it.
내가 완전히 파괴할게요
Once and for all.
But only if you tell me
where he hid it?
숨겨진 곳을 알려 줘요
You do know, where he hid it?
'그'가 보관을
어디에 숨겼는지 알죠?
Don't you, Helena?
You just have to tell me.
말해 줘요
Please!
부탁해요
Strange!
이상해
You remind me of him a bit.
너한테서
'그'의 기운이 느껴져
It's here, in the castle.
여기 있어
성안에
모든 게 숨겨진 방에
In the place where
everything is hidden.
If you have to ask...
물으면
... you will never know.
영원히 알 수 없지만
If you know...
알고 있으면
묻기만 하면 돼
... you need only ask.
Thank you!
고마워요
Tell Professor McGonagall. Remus and
I will handle this side of the castle.
맥고나걸 교수님께
여기는 내가 맡겠다고 해
Yes, sir!
네
Hey Dean, on second thoughts, tell Professor McGonagall
we might need one or two more wands this side.
아니, 다시 생각해 봤는데
마법사 두어 명
더 보내 달라고 해
It is the quality of one's convictions
that determine his success...
승패는 의지에
달려 있는 거야
... not the number of followers.
숫자는 상관없지
Who said that?
누가 그래?
Me.
내가!
You okay, Freddie?
괜찮아, 프레디?
Yeah.
응
Me too.
나도
Harry talks in his sleep.
해리가 잠자면서
말하는 거 알아?
Do you know this?
No, of course, not!
나야 모르지
Yeah?
You and whose army?
누구 군대지?
You do it.
- 네가 해
- 난 못해
I can't.
Yes, you can!
아니야, 할 수 있어
Neville!
네빌!
That went well.
제대로 부쉈네
Get inside! This way!
Take cover! Take cover
전부 안으로 들어가!
몸을 숨겨!
Stupefy
스투페파이!
Ginny, Neville!
You alright?
지니, 네빌
괜찮아?
Never better!
최상이야! 불도 내뿜을 수 있겠어!
루나 봤어?
I feel like I can spit fire!
Have you seen Luna up here?
Luna?
I'm mad for her. I think it's about time I told
her since we'll probably both be dead by dawn.
- 루나?
- 내가 좋아하거든
이제 고백하려고
새벽이 되면 죽을 테니까
I know.
알아
Bloody hell!
We'll never find him on this.
빌어먹을, 못 찾겠어
Here he is!
- 여기
- 좋아
- Just now...
- Brilliant!
He just vanished.
사라졌어, 금방 있었는데
I just now I saw it.
Maybe he's gone to the
Room of Requirement.
'필요의 방'에 들어가면
It doesn't show up on the map,
does it?
지도에 안 나타나지?
네가 그랬잖아
You said that last year.
That's right, I... I did.
그래
Let's go.
거기로 가자
Brilliant!
대단하네
Come on!
따라와!
Well, well...
이런
What brings you here, Potter?
여긴 왜 왔지, 해리?
I could ask you the same.
내가 물어볼 말이야
You have something of mine.
내 지팡이 갖고 있지?
I'd like it back.
내놔
What's wrong with the one you have?
- 지금 가진 지팡이는?
- 어머니 거야
It's my mother's.
It's powerful, but it's...
강력하지만
내 거하곤 달라서
... not the same.
Doesn't quite understand me.
나랑 안 맞아
You know what I mean?
무슨 말인지 알지?
Why didn't you tell her?
우리가 잡혔을 때
왜 나를 도와줬지?
Bellatrix?
벨라트릭스 앞에서?
You knew it was me.
나라는 걸 알면서
모른 척해 줬잖아
You didn't say anything.
Come on, Draco!
어서, 드레이코
바보처럼 굴지 말고 놈을 해치워
Don't be a prat.
Do it!
Easy!
가만있어
Expelliarmus
엑스펠리아르무스
Avada Kedavra
아바다 케다브라
Stupefy
스투페파이
This is my girlfriend,
you bloody gits!
내 여자 친구야
이 바보들아!
Got it!
찾았어!
도망쳐!
They've set the bloody place on fire!
고일이 불을 질러!
Come on!
This way!
이쪽이야!
We can't leave them!
구해 줘야 해!
He's joking, right?
농담이지?
If we die for them,
Harry, I'm gonna kill you!
쟤들 때문에 우리가 죽으면
너를 죽일 거야!
Harry!
해리!
My Lord?
주인님?
Avada Kedavra!
아바다 케다브라
Come Nagini, I need to keep you safe.
가자, 내기니
여기 있으면 위험해
It's the snake....
뱀이야!
... and she's the last one.
뱀이 마지막 호크룩스야
It's the last Horcrux.
Look inside him, Harry.
'그'의 마음을 읽어 봐
Find out where he is,
if you find him, we can find the snake.
어디 있는지 알아내면
뱀도 찾을 수 있어
And we can end this!
그럼 다 끝나
My Lord...
주인님?
Might it be less...
현명하게…
I should not be more prudent to call off
this attack.
공격을 중지시키고
주인님이 직접
Simply seek the boy.
꼬마를 찾는 게
현명하지 않을까요?
Yourself.
I do not need to seek the boy...
내가 녀석을
찾을 필요는 없다
... before the night is out,
he will come to me! Do you understand?
녀석이 날 찾아올 테니!
알았나?
Look at me!
나를 봐라!
How can you live with yourself,
Lucius?
수치스럽지도 않나, 루시우스?
I don't know.
압니다
Go and find Severus.
세베루스를 찾아서
Bring him to me.
내게 데려와라
I know where he is.
어디 있는지 알겠어
Come on!
가자!
크루시오!
No!
안돼!
You have performed extra-ordinary magic
with this wand, My Lord,
주인님께선 오늘 밤
이 지팡이로
... in the last few hours alone.
위대한 마법을
보여 주셨습니다
No!
아니
No! I am extra-ordinary.
But the wand resists me.
난 위대하지만
지팡이가 나를 거부한다
There is no wand more powerful.
Ollivander himself has said it.
이것보다 강한
지팡이는 없다고
올리밴더가 그랬습니다
Tonight, when the boy comes.
It will not fail you, I am sure of it...
오늘 밤 녀석이 오면
이 지팡이의 능력을 아시게 될 겁니다
It answers to you, and you only.
이 지팡이는
주인님께만 복종합니다
Does it?
그런가?
My Lord?
주인님?
The wand, does it truly answer to me?
이 지팡이가
내게만 복종하는가?
You're a clever man, Severus.
넌 영리하니까
Surely you must know...
알고 있겠지
- Where does its true loyalty lie?
- With you...
이 지팡이가
누구에게 복종하지?
주인님이지요
Of course, My Lord.
의심의 여지가 없습니다
The Elder Wand cannot serve me properly,
because I am not its true master.
이 지팡이가
내 뜻대로 안 되는 건
내가 진정한 주인이 아니라서다
The Elder Wand belongs to the
wizard who killed its last owner.
옛 주인을 죽인 자가
진짜 주인이지
You killed Dumbledore, Severus.
덤블도어를 죽인 건
바로 너였어
While you live, the Elder
Wand cannot truly be mine.
네가 살아 있는 한
이 지팡이는 내 것이 아니야
You've been a good and faithful servant,
Severus.
넌 내게 충실한 하인이었다
But only I can live forever.
하지만 오직 나만이
영생을 누릴 수 있지
My Lord...
주인님
Nagini, kill!
내기니, 죽여라
Take it...
Take it up, please!
내 눈물을 받아라
받아
부탁한다
아무 병이나 줘, 빨리!
Give me something!
Quickly, a flask. Anything!
펜시브로 가져가
Take them to the Pensieve.
Look at me...
나를 봐라
You really have your mother's eyes.
눈이 엄마를 닮았어
You've fought valiantly,
but in vain...
용맹하게 싸웠지만
헛될 뿐이다
I do not wish this. Every drop of magical
blood spilled is a terrible waste.
난 마법사들이
피를 흘리는 것을
원치 않는다
I, therefore command
my forces to retreat...
그래서 내 군대에게
퇴각을 명했다
In their absence,
dispose your dead with dignity,
죽은 마법사들의
장례를 치러줘라
Harry Potter,
I now speak directly to you.
해리 포터, 잘 들어라
On this night, you have allowed your friends
to die for you, rather than face me yourself.
넌 친구들을
죽음으로 몰아넣고
나와 대적하지 않았으니
There is no greater dishonor.
Join me in the Forbidden Forrest...
크나큰 치욕이다
금지된 숲으로 와서
네 운명에 맞서라
... and confront your fate.
If you do not do this, I shall kill every last man,
woman and child who tries to conceal you from me.
나타나지 않으면
너를 숨겨 주는 모든 마법사들을
남녀노소 불문
모조리 죽이겠다
Where's everybody?
다 어디 갔지?
Harry?
해리
Oh, come on!
Don't be sad on it, she's passed.
왜 그러는 거야?
애가 죽었어
There, she's gone.
저기도 죽었고…
괴물!
Freak! Come here! I'm gonna tell mommy!
You're freak!
이리 와!
엄마한테 이를 거야
넌 괴물이야!
넌 괴물이야, 릴리
You're freak, Lily!
Come here!
이리 와!
She's jealous.
She's ordinary and you're special.
질투하는 거야
자기는 평범하고 넌 특별하니까
그런 말 마, 세베루스
That's not true, Severus.
Gryffindor!
그리핀도르!
- Hi, I'm James.
- Hi, I'm Lily.
- 안녕, 난 제임스야
- 난 릴리
Just like your father.
아비를 빼닮았군
Don't say a word against my father!
우리 아빠를 욕하지 마요!
피가 흐르고
하인과 주인이
다시 하나가 된다!
Masters shall be reunited once more!
Severus.
세베루스
No, don't kill me!
안돼
나를 죽이지 마요
The prophecy did not
refer to a woman.
예언이 말한 건
여자가 아니었네
It spoke about a boy born
at the end of the July.
7월 말에 태어난
사내애를 말한 거지
Yes, but he thinks it's her son!
'그'가 그녀 아들을
지목했어요
He intends to hunt them down and
to kill them.
찾아내서 죽일 겁니다
Hide him... hide them all.
I beg you!
제발 그녀와 아이를
숨겨 주세요
What would you give me in exchange,
Severus?
그에 대한 대가는?
- Anything.
- Harry...
뭐든지 할게요
해리, 너무너무 사랑해
Harry, you were so loved.
So loved!
Harry, mama loves you.
엄마는 너를 사랑해
Dadda loves you.
아빠도 너를 사랑해
Harry, be safe.
해리, 살아남아
Be strong.
강해져라
Avada Kedavra!
아바다 케다브라!
그녀를 안전하게
지켜 준다 했잖아요
You said you would keep her safe.
Lily and James...
릴리와 제임스는
잘못된 선택을 했어
... put their faith in the wrong person,
Severus.
Rather like you.
자네처럼…
The boy survives.
아이는 살아남았어
He doesn't need protection,
the Dark Lord has gone.
어둠의 마왕은 사라졌어요
The Dark Lord will return.
다시 돌아올 거야
And when he does, the boy
will be in terrible danger!
그렇게 되면
아이 목숨이 위험해
He has her eyes.
눈이 엄마를 닮았다네
If you truly loved her...
그녀를 진심으로
사랑했다면…
No one, can know.
내 임무는 비밀로 해줘요
I shall never reveal the best of you,
Severus.
자네의 깊은 마음을
숨겨 달라?
Your word?
약속해요
Can you risk your life every day
to protect the boy?
아이를 지키려다
자네가 위험해져도?
... He possesses no measurable talent, his arrogance rivals
even that of his father and he seems to relish in his fame...
재능도 없고
아빠를 닮아 건방져요
유명세를 즐기고요
Don't say a word against my father!
아빠를 욕하지 마요!
James Potter, lazy, arrogant.
제임스 포터?
게으르고 건방져
- My father was a great man!
- Your father was a swine!
아빠는 훌륭한 분이셨어요!
비열한 놈이었다!
Drink it, it will contain the curse to
your hand, for the time being.
다 마셔요
저주가 퍼지는 걸
막아 줄 겁니다
- It will spread, Albus.
- How long?
오래 못 가겠지만…
내가 얼마나 살 수 있지?
Maybe a year.
한 1년쯤
Don't ignore me, Severus.
내 부탁을 들어줘, 세베루스
하모니아 넥테르 파서스
We both know Lord Voldemort has ordered
the Malfoy boy to murder me.
볼드모트가 말포이에게
나를 죽이라고 시켰어
But should he fail, I should presume
the Dark Lord will turn to you.
만약 걔가 실패하면
어둠의 마왕이
자네한테 시킬 거야
You must be the one to kill me,
Severus.
반드시 자네가
나를 죽여야 해
It is the only way.
그 방법뿐이야
Only then,
will the Dark Lord trust you completely.
그래야 어둠의 마왕이
자네를 완전히 믿을 거야
아바다 케다브라
It will come a time, when Harry Potter,
must be told something.
해리 포터가
알게 될 때가 올 거야
But you must wait, until Voldemort
is at his most vulnerable.
볼드모트가 약해질 때를
기다려야 해
알게 되다니, 뭘요?
Must be told what?
On the night, Lord Voldemort went
to Godric's Hollow to kill Harry...
볼드모트가
해리를 죽이려 할 때
And Lily Potter cast
herself between them...
릴리가 몸을 던져
... the curse rebounded.
저주가 튕겨 나갔어
When that happens,
a part of Voldemort's soul...
그때 볼드모트의
영혼 일부가
... latched itself onto the only
living thing it could find...
주변에 유일하게
살아 있는 것에 붙었지
... Harry himself.
바로 해리야
There's a reason Harry
can speak with snakes...
그래서 해리가
뱀과 대화를 하고
There's a reason he can look into
Lord Voldemort's mind...
볼드모트의 마음을
읽을 수 있는 거야
A part of Voldemort lives inside him.
그의 영혼 일부가
해리 안에 살아 있어
So, when the time comes...
그러니 때가 되면…
... the boy must die?
해리가 죽어야 된다고요?
Yes... yes.
He must die.
그래
죽어야 해
You've kept him alive, so he can
die at the proper moment?
때맞춰 죽으라고
그동안 지켜 준 거군요
You've been raising him
like a pig for slaughter.
잡아먹기 위해
돼지를 키우듯이!
Don't tell me now, that you've
grown to care for the boy.
갑자기 그 아이가
걱정이라도 되나?
Expecto Patronum
익스펙토 패트로눔
Lily!
릴리를…
After all this time?
아직도 사랑하나?
Always.
영원히…
So, when the time comes...
그러니까 때가 되면
해리가 죽어야 된다?
... the boy must die?
Yes.
그래, 죽어야 되지
He must die.
And Voldemort himself must do it.
반드시 볼드모트가
That is essential.
직접 죽여야 해
- Where've you been?
- I thought you went to the forest.
어디 갔었어?
- 숲에 간 줄 알았어
- 지금 갈 거야
I'm going there now.
Are you mad?
No...
미쳤어?
You can't give yourself up to him.
이제 와서 놈한테
항복하면 안 돼
What is it, Harry?
왜 그래, 해리?
What is it you know?
뭘 알아냈어?
There's a reason I can hear them.
내가 호크룩스 소리를
The Horcruxes.
들을 수 있는 건…
I think I've known for a while.
예전부터 알았어
And I think you have, too.
너도 눈치챘을 거야
- I'll go with you.
- No, kill the snake.
- 나도 갈래
- 아니, 뱀을 죽여
Kill the snake,
and then it's just him!
뱀을 죽이면 그자만 남아
나는 끝에서 열린다
I'm ready to die.
난 죽을 각오가 됐어
부활의 돌
Resurrection Stone.
용감한 우리 아들
You've been so brave, sweetheart.
왜 온 거예요?
Why are you here?
All of you.
다 함께?
We never left.
우리는 네 곁을
떠난 적 없단다
Does...
아파요?
Does it hurt?
죽는 거?
Dying?
잠드는 거랑 똑같아
Quicker than falling asleep.
얼마 안 남았다, 아들아
You're nearly there, son.
죄송해요
I'm sorry.
저를 위해 죽는 건
원치 않았는데…
I never wanted any
of you to die for me.
리무스, 아드님은…
And, Remus, your son?
우리 죽음이
헛되지 않음을 알게 되겠지
Others will tell him what his
mother and father died for.
언젠가는 이해할 거야
One day, he'll understand.
제 곁에 있어 줄 거죠?
You'll stay with me?
Until the end.
마지막 순간까지
'그'가 여러분을 못 봐요?
And he won't be able to see you?
그래
No.
우리는 여기 있다
We're here, you see.
Stay close to me.
곁에 있어 줘요
영원히…
Always.
No sign of him, My Lord.
놈이 안 보입니다
올 줄 알았는데
I thought he would come.
Harry, no!
해리?
안돼! 여긴 왜 온 거야?
- What're yeh doin' here?
- Quiet!
조용해!
Harry Potter...
해리 포터
... The Boy Who Lived...
살아남은 아이
... come to die.
죽으러 왔군
Avada Kedavra
아바다 케다브라
You can't help...
못 도와준다
해리
Harry, you wonderful boy...
착한 녀석
You brave, brave man!
넌 용감한 아이야
좀 걷자꾸나
Let us walk.
교수님, 저게 뭐죠?
Professor, what is that?
우리가 도울 수 있는
능력 밖의 것이지
Something beyond either of our help.
죽으러 온
볼드모트의 영혼 조각
A part of Voldemort sent here to die.
여기가 어디죠?
And exactly where are we?
나도 물어보려던 참이다
어디인 거 같니?
I was going to ask you that.
Where would you say that we are?
Well, it looks like
King's Cross station.
킹스크로스 역요
훨씬 깨끗하고
Only cleaner...
기차는 없지만요
... and without all the trains.
King's Cross, is that right?
킹스크로스 역, 그러니?
This is, as they say, 'your' party.
네 무의식이
여기를 선택한 거다
이제는 알겠지만
너와 볼드모트는
I expect you now realize that
you and Voldemort...
운명보다 더 강하게
연결돼 있어
... have been connected by
something other than fate.
Since that night in Godric's Hollow,
all those years ago.
네 부모님이 살해된
그날 밤 이후로…
그럼, 그게 사실인가요?
So it's true then, sir.
그의 영혼 일부가
제 안에 산다는 게?
A part of him lives within me,
doesn't it?
Did.
그랬지
It's been just destroyed many moments
ago by none other than Voldemort himself.
조금 전 볼드모트가
파괴하기 전까지는
넌 그가 뜻하지 않게 만든
호크룩스였어
You, were the Horcrux he
never meant to make, Harry.
저는 돌아가야겠죠?
- I have to go back, haven't I?
- Oh, that's up to you.
네게 달렸다
제가 선택할 수 있어요?
- I've a choice?
- Oh, yes!
그래
여기가 기차역이랬지?
We're in King's Cross, you say.
원한다면 기차를 탈 수 있어
I think if you so decide,
you'll be able to board a train.
어디로 가는 기차죠?
And where would it take me?
위로
On.
Voldemort has the Elder Wand.
볼드모트가
딱총나무 지팡이를 가졌어요
그래
True.
And the snake's still alive?
- 뱀은 살아 있고요
- 그래
Yes.
제게는 뱀을 죽일
무기가 없어요
And I've nothing to kill it with?
호그와트에선 도움을 청하는 자는
도움을 받게 돼 있지
Help will always be
given at Hogwarts, Harry.
To those who ask for it.
난 나 자신을
달변가로 자부해 왔다
I've always pride of myself
on my ability to turn a phrase.
말은, 내가 생각하건대
Words are,
in my not so humble opinion...
무궁무진한
마법의 원천으로서
... are most inexhaustible
source of magic.
상처를 주거나
또 상처를 치유해 주지
Capable of inflicting
injury and remedies.
지금 상황에선
이렇게 말해야겠구나
But I would in this case...
... amend my original
statement to this:
호그와트에선 도움받을 자격이
있는 자만이 도움을 받는다
Help, will always be
given at Hogwarts,
To those who deserve it.
죽은 자들을
불쌍히 여기지 마라
Do not pity the dead, Harry...
산 사람들을 불쌍히 여겨
Pity the living.
무엇보다 사랑 없이 사는
사람들을 불쌍히 여기렴
And above all...
... all those who live without love.
엄마의 패트로누스가
암사슴이었죠?
Professor, my mother's Patronus...
... was a doe, wasn't it?
스네이프 교수님도
그랬는데
As the same as Professor Snape's.
이상하지 않아요?
It's curious, don't you think?
생각해 보면
전혀 이상할 게 없다
Actually, if I think about it...
... it doesn't seem curious at all!
난 이제 가마
I'll be going now, Harry.
교수님?
Professor?
이게 현실인가요?
Is this all real?
아니면 제 머릿속에서
벌어지는 일인가요?
Or is it just happening
inside my head?
물론 네 머릿속에서
벌어지는 일이지
Of course it's happening
inside your head, Harry.
그렇다 해서 그게
현실이 아닌 건 아니다
Why should that mean,
that it's not real?
교수님?
저는 어떻게 하죠?
Professor?
What should I do?
교수님?
Professor!
주인님
My Lord, My Lord...
다치셨어요?
Are you hurt?
도움 따위는 필요 없어
I don't need your help.
일어나세요
꼬마는
The boy...
죽었어요?
Is he dead?
살아 있니?
Is he alive?
드레이코는 살아 있니?
Draco, is he alive?
죽었어요
Dead.
해그리드가
안고 오는 게 누구지?
Who is that?
Hagrid's carrying?
누구야?
Neville, who is it?
해리 포터는
Harry Potter...
죽었다!
- is dead!
- No!
안돼!
No!
Silence!
조용!
어리석은 것
Stupid girl!
해리 포터는 죽었다
Harry Potter...
... is dead!
오늘 이 순간부터
내가 너희들의
From this day forth...
... you'll put your faith in me.
주인이다
해리 포터는 죽었다!
Harry Potter is dead!
내게 충성을 맹세해라
And now it's the time
to declare yourself.
앞으로 나와
맹세하지 않으면
Come forward and join us...
죽이겠다
... or die!
드레이코
Draco!
Draco.
드레이코
이리 와
Come.
잘했다, 드레이코
Well done, Draco.
잘했어
Well done!
생각보다 적어 실망이군
Well, I must say I'd
hoped for better.
넌 누구냐?
And who might you be, young man?
네빌 롱바텀요
Neville Longbottom.
네빌, 네게 어울리는
자리를 주마
Well, Neville, I'm sure we can
find a place for you in our rank.
할 말이 있어요
I'd like to say something.
그래, 모두가 네 말을
듣고 싶을 거다
Well, Neville, I'm sure we'd all be
fascinated to hear what you have to say.
- 해리가 죽었다지만…
- 그만둬, 네빌
- Doesn't matter that Harry is gone.
- Stand down, Neville!
매일 사람들이 죽어요
People die everyday!
친구들, 가족…
Friends, family.
Yeah...
오늘 밤에는 해리를 잃었죠
We lost Harry tonight.
하지만 걔는
이 안에 있어요
He's still with us.
In here.
프레드
So as Fred, Remus...
리무스
통스
Tonks...
모두 다…
All of them.
그들의 죽음은
헛되지 않아요
They didn't die in vain.
당신 죽음은 헛되겠지
But you will.
당신이 틀렸으니까!
해리 심장은 우리를 위해 뛰었어!
Because you're wrong!
Harry's heart did beat for us.
For all of us!
모두를 위해!
전투는 아직 안 끝났어!
It's not over!
콘프링고!
Confringo
어딜 가? 돌아와!
루시우스!
당장 돌아와서 싸워!
Come on!
안돼! 돌아와!
'그'를 성으로 유인할게
뱀을 죽여야 해
All remain into the castle.
We have to kill the snake.
- 필요할 거야
- 네빌!
Neville!
내 딸은 안돼
이 못된 년!
Not my daughter, you bitch!
그렇지!
Hey, you were right...
스네이프 교수한테
지팡이가 말을 안 듣는다고 했지?
... when you told Professor Snape
that wand was failing you.
영원히 그럴 거야
It will always fail...
스네이프는 내가 죽였다
I killed Snape!
지팡이 주인이
스네이프가 아니라면?
But what if the wand never belonged
to Snape?
주인이 따로 있었다면?
What if its allegiance is always
to someone else?
톰 리들, 시작처럼 끝내자
Oh, come on, Tom...
Let's finish this the way we started.
우리 둘이서!
Together!
Die!
나는 늘 너에 대한
기대가 컸어
지팡이를 잃어버려서
한참을 찾았어
가운 속에 있었지 뭐야
간신히 찾아서 몇 놈 해치웠지
물론, 당신만큼은 아니지만
해리
Harry!
딱총나무 지팡이가
왜 그의 말을 안 들었지?
Why didn't it work for him?
The Elder Wand?
진짜 주인은 따로 있었어
It answered to somebody else.
스네이프가
주인이라고 죽였지만
When he killed Snape, he thought
the wand would become his.
지팡이 주인은
스네이프가 아니었어
But the thing is...
The wand never belonged to Snape.
천문탑에서 덤블도어를
무장 해제시킨 건 드레이코였어
It was Draco, who disarmed Dumbledore
that night in the Astronomy tower.
그때부터
지팡이의 주인은 걔였어
From that moment on and the wand
answered him,
말포이 저택에서
Until, the other night
when I disarmed Draco.
내가 녀석을
무장 해제시킬 때까지
At Malfoy Manor.
그렇다면…
So, that means...
- 이제는 내 거야
- 우리 그걸로 뭘 할까?
It's mine!
- What should we do with it?
- We?
우리?
세상에서 제일 강력한
지팡이잖아
Just saying, that's the Elder Wand.
The most powerful wand in the world.
그것만 있으면
아무도 우리를 못 이겨
With that, he'd be invincible.
19년 후
같이 가자
Together.
잘 지내라, 사이좋게!
가방
- Bag?
- Yeah.
잠바
Jumper?
보고 싶을 거야
I'm gonna miss you.
저기 온다
Here they come.
아빠, 슬리데린에
뽑히면 어떡하지?
Dad?
What if I am put in Slytherin?
알버스 세베루스 포터
Albus Severus Potter. You were named
after two Headmasters of Hogwarts.
네 이름은 호그와트 교장
두 분 이름을 땄어
한 분은 슬리데린이었고
One of them was a Slytherin. And he
was the bravest man I've ever known.
아주 용감하셨지
아무튼, 뽑히면?
- But just say if I am...
- Then Slytherin house...
슬리데린이 젊고 멋진
마법사를 얻은 거지
... will have gained a
wonderful young wizard.
정말 거기가 싫으면
그리핀도르를 선택해
But listen...
If it really means that much to you,
you can choose Gryffindor.
분류 모자가
네 선택을 고려할 거야
The Sorting Hat takes
your choice into account.
진짜?
- Really?
- Really.
진짜!
탑승하세요!
준비됐어?
- Ready?
- Ready.
응